[Music]
hello I'm Barrick nutson and in this
session we are going to look at what
we've done for the job queue in this
wave and I would say with this wave we
technically already released it but it
belongs to this
wave I'm briefly touching upon what is
the job queue because most people use
it uh and then what's different
here in wave
two so first of all it's not so much a q
as it is a way to schedule background
tasks and we have a system command as
you can see in the screen where we
create a task and then we specify which
code you need to run which code you to
call if it if you have an error when to
run it uh and which record to
process but it's also an application
feature where we in the application have
um there are two examples on the screen
maybe we want to run a report or a code
unit maybe there are some parameters
maybe we want to re to reschedule it
when it's done so we can have a
recurrence
and there's one particular field that we
are going to touch upon in this
presentation which is the um category
code job Q category and that's used for
if you want only one of these jobs to
run at the same time is typically used
for sales and purchase order posting
where you only can post one sales order
or purchase order at the same time if
you want to avoid
locking um otherwise you don't need this
field so how does it work or how did it
work
before so the job starts and the first
thing we do is that we look at does it
have a category code like the one which
I just
showed uh if no then we just run the
task and we're done if yes there is a
category code then we check does anyone
else with the same category run no then
we run and we're done otherwise
we figura figuratively hang up and try
again later actually just like when you
try to call the pizza delivery uh or the
doctor
so you you make a try if it's busy you
try again
later and that works
fine if very few people schedule this at
the same time but if there a long Q it
means you need
to call very often like the pizza
delivery or doctor you need to try many
times before you get through but also it
means that the execu Fusion order is
random even you were the first to call
or sorry the second to call obviously uh
you may also be the last to get through
and again if there's a long queue we'll
have to reschedule a lot again similar
to you needing to call a lot of times
before you finally get through and it's
this specific thing that we have changed
um now so if you remember
this schema
then so the normal flow is the same but
if there's a category and someone else
is running then we go to sleep so we set
status to waiting and we schedule a task
that is not ready and then we actually
don't do anything
more the process that was running
remember and someone else was running at
this time when they're done they will go
out and say activate next next in Q
meaning you or someone
else uh and then they're done and you
can start your
turn so this is more like actually
lining up in a queue as supposed as
you're supposed
to um and we also get the correct
execution order because you know you
have a number and you keep that number
in a
queue so if you're first in your Al
first
out uh and finally since we are to pick
the next number down here we can
actually introduce priority we can allow
someone to skip the queue because we
actually did have a customer who had a
lot of sales postings and purchase
postings all with very very large orders
thousands of lines so each single order
would be
minutes and some sometimes they would
have queued up half an
hour uh of worth of uh jobs
waiting but they may have a you know
something very urgent that they want to
prioritize maybe the truck was waiting
outside or
whatever so that's why we introduced
priority as well within that
category uh and that's basically it so
the the only thing we did we added a new
status code waiting and that Corr
responds to sleeping if you
will thank you that's it